<?xml version="1.0"?>
<sect2>
  <sect2info>
    <title>Band Pass Filter</title>
  </sect2info>
  <para>This filter is a convenience wrapper for an FIR filter and a firdes taps generating function. Sample rate, cutoff frequency, and transition width are in Hertz. The beta paramater only applies to the Kaiser window.
	</para>
  <screenshot>
    <graphic fileref="images/band_pass_filter.png"/>
  </screenshot>
  <sect3>
    <sect3info>
      <title>FIR Type</title>
    </sect3info>
    <para>Specifies the data type of the input and output streams, with the option of either decimation or interpolation. Also specifies whether the taps are real or complex. Complex taps allow the bandpass filter to be asymmetric in the frequency domain, ie: complex poles don't necessarily appear in conjugate pairs.</para>
    <informaltable frame="none">
      <tgroup cols="2">
        <tbody>
          <row>
            <entry>Complex-&gt;Complex (Real Taps) (Decim)</entry>
            <entry>Input and output streams are complex, with the option to decimate the output. This filter will have the same pass bands on both the positive and negative halves of the spectrum.</entry>
          </row>
          <row>
            <entry>Complex-&gt;Complex (Real Taps) (Interp)</entry>
            <entry>Input and output streams are complex, with the option to interpolate the output. This filter will have the same pass bands on both the positive and negative halves of the spectrum.</entry>
          </row>
          <row>
            <entry>Float-&gt;Float (Real Taps) (Decim)</entry>
            <entry>Input and output streams are real, with the option to decimate the output.</entry>
          </row>
          <row>
            <entry>Float-&gt;Float (Real Taps) (Interp)</entry>
            <entry>Input and output streams are real, with the option to interpolate the output.</entry>
          </row>
          <row>
            <entry>Complex-&gt;Complex (Complex Taps) (Decim)</entry>
            <entry>Input and output streams are complex, with the option to decimate the output. This filter will have only one pass band. High and low cutoff frequencies can be positive or negative.</entry>
          </row>
          <row>
            <entry>Complex-&gt;Complex (Complex Taps) (Interp)</entry>
            <entry>Input and output streams are complex, with the option to interpolate the output. This filter will have only one pass band. High and low cutoff frequencies can be positive or negative.</entry>
          </row>
          <row>
            <entry>Float-&gt;Complex (Complex Taps) (Decim)</entry>
            <entry>Input stream is real while the output stream is complex, with the option to decimate the output. This filter will have only one pass band. High and low cutoff frequencies can be positive or negative.</entry>
          </row>
          <row>
            <entry>Float-&gt;Complex (Complex Taps) (Interp)</entry>
            <entry>Input stream is real while the output stream is complex, with the option to interpolate the output. This filter will have only one pass band. High and low cutoff frequencies can be positive or negative.</entry>
          </row>
        </tbody>
      </tgroup>
    </informaltable>
  </sect3>
  <sect3>
    <sect3info>
      <title>Decimation/Interpolation</title>
    </sect3info>
    <para><emphasis>Type: </emphasis>int</para>
    <para>Decimation or interpolation can be selected through the FIR Type parameter. If resampling is not required set this parameter to 1.</para>
  </sect3>
  <sect3>
    <sect3info>
      <title>Gain</title>
    </sect3info>
    <para><emphasis>Type: </emphasis>real</para>
    <para>Sets the gain of the filter.</para>
  </sect3>
  <sect3>
    <sect3info>
      <title>Sample Rate</title>
    </sect3info>
    <para><emphasis>Type: </emphasis>real</para>
    <para>Sets the sample rate of the filter, in Hz.</para>
  </sect3>
  <sect3>
    <sect3info>
      <title>Low Cutoff Freq</title>
    </sect3info>
    <para><emphasis>Type: </emphasis>real</para>
    <para>Sets the low cutoff frequency of the filter, in Hz. The low cutoff frequency must be less than the high cutoff frequency.</para>
  </sect3>
  <sect3>
    <sect3info>
      <title>High Cutoff Freq</title>
    </sect3info>
    <para><emphasis>Type: </emphasis>real</para>
    <para>Sets the high cutoff frequency of the filter, in Hz. The high cutoff frequency must be greater than the low cutoff frequency.</para>
  </sect3>
  <sect3>
    <sect3info>
      <title>Transition Width</title>
    </sect3info>
    <para><emphasis>Type: </emphasis>real</para>
    <para>Sets the transition width between the pass band and stop band. A small transition width will increase the length of the FIR filter.</para>
  </sect3>
  <sect3>
    <sect3info>
      <title>Window</title>
    </sect3info>
    <para>Specifies the window function that will be applied to the FIR filter.</para>
    <informaltable frame="none">
      <tgroup cols="2">
        <tbody>
          <row>
            <entry>Hamming</entry>
            <entry>Apply a Hamming window.</entry>
          </row>
          <row>
            <entry>Hann</entry>
            <entry>Apply a Hann window.</entry>
          </row>
          <row>
            <entry>Blackman</entry>
            <entry>Apply a Blackman window.</entry>
          </row>
          <row>
            <entry>Rectangular</entry>
            <entry>Apply a rectangular window.</entry>
          </row>
          <row>
            <entry>Kaiser</entry>
            <entry>Apply a Kaiser window. The Beta parameter can be controlled.</entry>
          </row>
        </tbody>
      </tgroup>
    </informaltable>
  </sect3>
  <sect3>
    <sect3info>
      <title>Beta</title>
    </sect3info>
    <para><emphasis>Type: </emphasis>real</para>
    <para>Beta parameter for the Kaiser window.</para>
  </sect3>
</sect2>
