<?xml version="1.0"?>
<sect2>
  <sect2info>
    <title>Frequency Xlating FIR Filter</title>
  </sect2info>
  <para>Implements a frequency-translating FIR filter. This is often used as a utitility channel selection block, as it performs frequency translation, channel selection and decimation in one step.</para>
  <screenshot>
    <graphic fileref="images/freq_xlating_fir_filter_xxx.png"/>
  </screenshot>
  <sect3>
    <sect3info>
      <title>Type</title>
    </sect3info>
    <para>Specifies the type of the input and output streams.</para>
    <informaltable frame="none">
      <tgroup cols="2">
        <tbody>
          <row>
            <entry>Complex-&gt;Complex (Complex Taps)</entry>
            <entry>Input and output streams are complex. Additionally, the filter taps can be complex.</entry>
          </row>
          <row>
            <entry>Complex-&gt;Complex (Real Taps)</entry>
            <entry>Input and output streams are complex. Additionally, the filter taps must be real.</entry>
          </row>
          <row>
            <entry>Float-&gt;Complex (Complex Taps)</entry>
            <entry>The input stream is real while the output stream is complex. Additionally, the filter taps can be complex.</entry>
          </row>
          <row>
            <entry>Float-&gt;Complex (Real Taps)</entry>
            <entry>The input stream is real while the output stream is complex. Additionally, the filter taps must be real.</entry>
          </row>
          <row>
            <entry>Short-&gt;Complex (Complex Taps)</entry>
            <entry>The input stream is a 16-bit short integer while the output stream is complex. Additionally, the filter taps can be complex.</entry>
          </row>
          <row>
            <entry>Short-&gt;Complex (Real Taps)</entry>
            <entry>The input stream is a 16-bit short integer while the output stream is complex. Additionally, the filter taps must be real.</entry>
          </row>
        </tbody>
      </tgroup>
    </informaltable>
  </sect3>
  <sect3>
    <sect3info>
      <title>Decimation</title>
    </sect3info>
    <para><emphasis>Type: </emphasis>int</para>
    <para>Specifies the decimation factor for the output. The output sample rate will be the specified sample rate divided by the decimation factor.</para>
  </sect3>
  <sect3>
    <sect3info>
      <title>Taps</title>
    </sect3info>
    <para><emphasis>Type: </emphasis>Same as Type.</para>
    <para>Enter a valid firdes expression or a valid Python list containing the taps (if designing filters using another method).</para>
  </sect3>
  <sect3>
    <sect3info>
      <title>Center Frequency</title>
    </sect3info>
    <para><emphasis>Type: </emphasis>real</para>
    <para>Specifies the center frequency. This is the frequency that will be shifted down to 0 Hz before the channel selection filter is applied.</para>
  </sect3>
  <sect3>
    <sect3info>
      <title>Sample Rate</title>
    </sect3info>
    <para><emphasis>Type: </emphasis>real</para>
    <para>Specifies the sample rate, in Hz.</para>
  </sect3>
</sect2>
