<?xml version="1.0"?>
<sect2>
  <sect2info>
    <title>Signal Source</title>
  </sect2info>
  <para>Used to generate a variety of signal types: Sine, Cosine, Square, Triangle and Sawtooth.</para>
  <screenshot>
    <graphic fileref="images/gr_sig_source_x.png"/>
  </screenshot>
  <sect3>
    <sect3info>
      <title>Output Type</title>
    </sect3info>
    <para>Specifies the data type of the output.</para>
    <informaltable frame="none">
      <tgroup cols="2">
        <tbody>
          <row>
            <entry>Complex</entry>
            <entry>Output is complex-valued.</entry>
          </row>
          <row>
            <entry>Float</entry>
            <entry>Output is real-valued.</entry>
          </row>
          <row>
            <entry>Int</entry>
            <entry>Output is a 32-bit integer.</entry>
          </row>
          <row>
            <entry>Short</entry>
            <entry>Output is a 16-bit integer.</entry>
          </row>
        </tbody>
      </tgroup>
    </informaltable>
  </sect3>
  <sect3><sect3info><title>Sample Rate</title></sect3info><para><emphasis>Type: </emphasis>real</para>Specifies the output sample rate.</sect3>
  <sect3>
    <sect3info>
      <title>Waveform</title>
    </sect3info>
    <para>Specifies the output waveform.</para>
    <informaltable frame="none">
      <tgroup cols="2">
        <tbody>
          <row>
            <entry>Constant</entry>
            <entry>Output is a constant value equal to the Amplitude parameter plus the Offset parameter. Note that Amplitude is only real while Offset can be complex. The Constant Source block provides the same functionality.</entry>
          </row>
          <row>
            <entry>Sine</entry>
            <entry>Output is a sine wave with peak amplitude configured by the Amplitude parameter and average value set by the Offset paramater.</entry>
          </row>
          <row>
            <entry>Cosine</entry>
            <entry>Output is a cosine wave with peak amplitude configured by the Amplitude parameter and average value set by the Offset paramater.</entry>
          </row>
          <row>
            <entry>Square</entry>
            <entry>Output is a square wave with peak-to-peak amplitude configured by the Amplitude parameter and the average value set by Offset + Amplitude/2. Note that in the Complex case, the imaginary signal is simply another square wave that has been shifted by ninety degrees.</entry>
          </row>
          <row>
            <entry>Triangle</entry>
            <entry>Output is a triangle wave with peak-to-peak amplitude configured by the Amplitude parameter and the average value set by Offset + Amplitude/2. Note that in the Complex case, the imaginary signal is simply another triangle wave that has been shifted by ninety degrees.</entry>
          </row>
          <row>
            <entry>Sawtooth</entry>
            <entry>Output is a positive-going sawtooth wave with peak-to-peak amplitude configured by the Amplitude parameter and the average value set by Offset + Amplitude/2. Note that in the Complex case, the imaginary signal is simply another sawtooth wave that has been shifted by ninety degrees.</entry>
          </row>
        </tbody>
      </tgroup>
    </informaltable>
  </sect3>
  <sect3><sect3info><title>Frequency</title></sect3info><para><emphasis>Type: </emphasis>real</para>Specifies the output frequency of the Signal Source. Note that aliasing will occur if the frequency is set higher than half of the sample rate.</sect3>
  <sect3><sect3info><title>Amplitude</title></sect3info><para><emphasis>Type: </emphasis>real</para>Specifies the peak amplitude (Sine and Cosine) or the peak-to-peak amplitude (Square, Triangle and Sawtooth). When using the Constant output, typically this is set to 0 and the Offset parameter is used.</sect3>
  <sect3><sect3info><title>Offset</title></sect3info><para><emphasis>Type: </emphasis>Complex</para>Specifies the offset that is added to the generated waveform.</sect3>
</sect2>
