<?xml version="1.0"?>
<sect2>
  <sect2info>
    <title>Variable Config</title>
  </sect2info>
  <para>This block represents a variable that can be read from a config file, as a way to make flowgraph save the settings between runs.
	</para>
  <screenshot>
    <graphic fileref="images/variable_config.png"/>
  </screenshot>
  <sect3>
    <sect3info>
      <title>Default Value</title>
    </sect3info>
    <para><emphasis>Type: </emphasis>Same as Type</para>
    <para>Sets the default value if the parameter named in the Option field is not found in the specified Config File.</para>
  </sect3>
  <sect3>
    <sect3info>
      <title>Type</title>
    </sect3info>
    <para>Specifies the data type of the Variable.</para>
    <informaltable frame="none">
      <tgroup cols="2">
        <tbody>
          <row>
            <entry>Float</entry>
            <entry>Variable is interpreted as a real value.</entry>
          </row>
          <row>
            <entry>Int</entry>
            <entry>Variable is interpreted as an integer value.</entry>
          </row>
          <row>
            <entry>Bool</entry>
            <entry>Variable is interpreted as a Boolean (True/False) value.</entry>
          </row>
          <row>
            <entry>String</entry>
            <entry>Variable is interpreted as a string.</entry>
          </row>
        </tbody>
      </tgroup>
    </informaltable>
  </sect3>
  <sect3>
    <sect3info>
      <title>Config File</title>
    </sect3info>
    <para><emphasis>Type: </emphasis>file_open</para>
    <para>Specifies the file that will be used to save the flowgraph configuration. In some versions of GNURadio, this file needs to exist already. You can create a new empty file on the command line using the "touch" command or create a file through the Linux file browser.</para>
  </sect3>
  <sect3>
    <sect3info>
      <title>Section</title>
    </sect3info>
    <para><emphasis>Type: </emphasis>string</para>
    <para>Specifies which section the variable will be placed in. This allows grouping of variables into different sections depending on the function.</para>
  </sect3>
  <sect3>
    <sect3info>
      <title>Option</title>
    </sect3info>
    <para><emphasis>Type: </emphasis>string</para>
    <para>What the variable will be called in the config file. The config file will be plain text, and can be edited using a text editor.</para>
  </sect3>
  <sect3>
    <sect3info>
      <title>WriteBack</title>
    </sect3info>
    <para><emphasis>Type: </emphasis>raw</para>
    <para> To save the value back into the config file, enter the name of another variable into the writeback param. When the other variable is changed at runtime, the config file will be re-written.</para>
  </sect3>
</sect2>
